CURRICULUM VITAE



IBRAHIM QURAISHI MOHAMMED Position: Document Control Manager Mobile: 0501952334

Email:

Ibrahim_4046@yahoo.com

Career Objective

Seeking a career in Document Control to developing Construction field and every growing organization that is creative, transparent and provide facilities for enhancing skills and meeting modern and latest organization requirement both practically and academically coupled with functional experience and to contribute to the development of the organization and myself looking forward to work with any reputable organization in the field of Document Control to offer the overall 12 years experiences.

Work Experience (12 yrs)

M/s Saudi Binladin Group (ABCD)

From April 2011 - Present

Working as *Document Control Manager* KAIA Airport Project (Jeddah)

Achievements

Introduced new software to the Company, methods and procedures relating to Document Control that resulted in streamlining the process.

Achieved goal of bringing about heightened recognition of the benefits of document control.

Successfully ran document control function for King AbdulAziz International Airport Project that included deliverable scheduling, using Document Control Software and Primavera. The task completed under budget and ahead of time.

Regularly audited to ISO 9000+ standard either from within the company or by Lloyd's and/or Standards client appointed auditors. Never failed an audit.

Responsibilities

Successfully Co-ordinate the entire Document Control functions for the Perth Office and Technical Information Centre. This included staffing levels and training. Duties included hands-on lead role whilst also responsible as a project based document controller for package 422.

Project responsibilities included: Setting up deliverables (drawings, specifications, reports, manuals, etc), data bases with budget hours and progress measurement systems from scratch, logging, recording, copying and distribution of all deliverables including vendor deliverables, progress reporting each fortnight or as required against deliverables (including Vendors) and project close-out/archiving.

Further important responsibilities included liaison with the client to ensure timely delivery of all materials requiring hand-over and hand-over format, which was completed on or ahead of time. Other duties also included liaison with external businesses for reprographic services.

Duties

- Under minimal supervision performs a variety of document control functions for a project or department.
- Plans, organizes, and implements systems for efficient document processing of all communications, supplier documents, design documents, construction documents or other internal or external documents.
- Coordinates the flow of documents between project operations, engineering disciplines, construction team, or other department groups. Incumbent is typically responsible for a small to mediumsized project.
- Will have knowledge of both the work processes of document control and also the use of electronic systems used to manage documentation.
- Processes one or more document types through all procedural steps in accordance with well-defined procedures and guidelines. Ensures that pre-established document control requirements (e.g., which document numbering system will be used; how many and which signatures will be required for certain approvals, etc.) are satisfactorily met throughout the duration of the project.
- Implements document/data management solutions with a primary focus on document control and records management. Administers data/document management applications.

- Receives, tracks, and monitors documents using standard document management programs to register documents, maintain databases, and produces logs, transmittals, and other reports as required. Enters data and produces reports using other standard office automation or department-specific computer applications. Initiates and replies to routine correspondence related to area of responsibility.
- Keeps abreast of department technologies, techniques and services relevant to area of responsibility. Works with other staff members as needed to develop and improve services. Responds to changing technology environment and participates in decision making activities relating to customers' needs.
- Provides assistance to users in capturing and locating electronic information.
- Maintains an established data distribution system and schedule for the assigned project based upon client, project, department, and supplier requirements. May revise system or schedule as required to ensure timely approvals and distribution. Expedites review, signature approval, and release of supplier and internally produced documents.
- Verifies retention requirements, arranges document cataloging, packing, and long-term storage or disposal of appropriate documents at time of closeout. Manages scheduled destruction of archived documents according to company and/or Client guidelines; provides assistance with document retrieval.
- Assists junior document control staff to ensure effective implementation of project-specific procedures.
- Serves as liaison between support group, home office and field personnel. Interfaces with groups inside and outside the organizatio.
- Delegates and directs the work activities of project document control team.
- Performs other duties commensurate with functional level and responsibilities.
- Contributes as a team player who is deadline driven and works well with others.
- EDMS (Electronic Document Management System) using Primavera Contracts Manager.

From July 2010 - March 2011

M/s Dulb Trading & Contracting Co. (MEP Contractor)

Worked as Lead Document Controller Lamar Towers Project (Jeddah)

Lamar is an extraordinary concept, a truly unique landmark which brings the very best of the world to the shores of the Red Sea in Jeddah, creating what is surely the Kingdom's most desirable address with a total gross construction area of approximately 415,605 square meters.

Duties and Responsibilities

- Registering all incoming and outgoing correspondences, MoM,
 Drawings & technical submittals into the Expedition for easy tracking.
- •Responsible for Control / Track / Issue of complete project documentation such as incoming and outgoing correspondence, site instructions, change orders, RFI, NCR, Submittals and other forms of pertinent documents from the client and subcontractors.
- Set up document control filing system in by organizing, labeling
- Archiving, updating contract package documents.
- Co-ordination between Main Consultant & Contractor.
- Maintain Archive section up to date.
- Fulfill Client's requirements of handing over.
- Successful closeout and handover of documentation from Projects.
- Proactively engage Lead or Team Lead Document Controllers on deviations from standards/procedures.
- Maintain Tender/Contract Documents.
- Coordinates the training for all new employees on the Documentation System.
- · Audits documentation system periodically.
- Monitoring and tracking of controlled documents from initiation to implementation.
- Convene meeting as & when necessary.

- Maintain Variation Orders, Claims & QS reports log.
- Preparation of Monthly Reports for submitting to Client.
- Daily backup (electronic copy) of project documents.
- Follow-up with team members for "open" status items
- Maintain ISO standard for Project Documentation
- Update drawings in accordance with Drawing Register.

From Feb 2004 - June 2010

M/s Saudi Diyar Consultants

Worked as Sr. Document Controller on EMAAR Jeddah Gate Project (Jeddah)

Duties and Responsibilities

- Ensure the timely turnaround of documentation issued internally or received externally.
- Working on document control oriented system Primavera Contract Management (Oracle).
- Supervise and Control the receipt and register of specifications, drawings, & documents for projects.
- Control the Issuance of documents and drawings from all Sub-Contractors.
- Monitor and supervise in maintaining submittal logs, transmittals accordingly as per Company Procedure.
- Maintain files of all Internal and External Correspondence and technical documents.
- Coordinate with Division/ Department/ Project Managers & Senior Staff with regards to Document requirements, issues and compliance.
- Maintain ISO standard by following & implementing the company procedures and its objectives in the world of business.
- Maintaining of all Correspondence Log
- Coordinate between the sites, head office and the all Sub-Contractors.
- Follow-up of submittals with the CM in timely manner.
- Trained in Internal Audit Procedures
- Responsible to maintain all outgoing/Incoming correspondence.
- Responsible for all Document Control Department for documentation, drawings and Submittals overall filing system of the project as per SBG standard.

 Prepare daily report of the receivable/submission of all documents/Submittals.

From July 2003 to Jan 2004 (Air wings Travel) worked as Executive Secretary to the General Manager of a leading travel agency in the firm based in Jeddah, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.

My basic job responsibilities are the following to organize the meetings for all the department managers, preparing daily and monthly sales reports and follow up with department managers to ensure agreed activities are completed on time. And implement and manage a divisional follow-up system, Carry out any other tasks as delegated or designated by the General Manger and Coordinate and mange diary, travel and meeting request.

Work Experience in India

From April 2001 to May 2003

✓ Haji Mohammed Vazeer & Sons M.J. Market, Hyderabad, India Position: Executive Secretary

Job Profile: In charge of all the correspondence of the company, this has their own production of Marble, Granite as well as polish stones. My job was to take care of the product dispatch to the customer properly with all the formalities of billing and also daily visits to the banks and few site works also.

✓ Siddique & Associates

Basher Bagh, Hyderabad, India

Position: Secretary

Job Profile: My duties were to handle all the responsibilities of a secretary like drafting letters to various companies regarding the quotations along with all the future correspondence. The company deals with all the construction related materials. I used to maintain the daily summary report for the work done.

Educational Qualification

Bachelor of Commerce from C.S.J.M University (Kanpur)

Technical Qualification

HDSE (Higher Diploma in Software Engineering) ICC Computer Education Hyderabad, India.

Computer Skills:

Knowledge in using the Personal Computer (PC) with the following software.

- ✓ Operating System: Post Graduation Diploma in computer
- ✓ MS Windows (Operating System)
- ✓ MS Office (Word, Excel, Access & Power Point)
- ✓ MS Outlook Express
- ✓ Internet Explorer
- ✓ MS Dos Utility

Personal Profile

Name : Mohammed Ibrahim Quraishi

Date of Birth : Nov 21, 1978
Nationality : Indian
Marital Status : Married
Religion : Islam

Languages Known : English with Fluency, Urdu, Hindi &

Little Arabic

Iqama Status : Transferable

Valid : Saudi Driven License

Mobile : 0501952334

Email : Ibrahim_4046@yahoo.com

Mohammed Ibrahim Quraishi